# MERRILL KOSHY THOMAS

+971-56-347-5735 / merrillkoshy@gmail.com / LinkedIn: in/merrill-koshy-thomas / Dubai, UAE

#### **FULL STACK ENGINEER**

Full Stack Engineer versed with various stacks, with over 6 years of hands-on experience designing, developing and implementing solutions using JavaScript. Successfully completed over 20 projects for userbases in millions. Orchestrated complete digital transitions of traditional businesses. Constantly updated with the latest development tools and practices.

**Portfolio**: <a href="https://merrillkoshy.github.io">https://merrillkoshy.github.io</a> **GitHub**: <a href="https://github.com/merrillkoshy">https://github.com/merrillkoshy</a>

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Frontend, Backend, Databases, CI/CD
- Cross-Platform Mobile App Development
- Agile Methodologies & Development
- Project Management

- MERNstack, JAMstack
- Progressive Web Apps, NPM Packaging
- System & Solution Architecture
- Artworks & Creative Design

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Senior Full Stack Developer**

Incomlend Pte Ltd - Dubai, UAE

June 2022 - Present

**Project**: Incomlend and LCLite FinTech Platform tooling. Tasked with Software Architecture Rationalisation, developing the component library required to be used in both platforms.

- Squad collaboration using Slack and management using JIRA.
- Deployments, issue-tracking and code review through GitLab.
- Development primarily in TypeScript-ReactJS, component rendering and documentation through Storybook and JSDoc, packaging and versioning through NPM and RollupJS.
- Engineered along with 2 other developers in a cross-functional team of 10, based in the parent company in Singapore.
- Created a tooling division dedicated to delivering isolated, versatile and highly performant React component package library, thereby reducing platform Front-End development time and effort and increasing platform FMP by approximately 30%.

#### Senior Associate | Full Stack Developer

PricewaterhouseCoopers - Dubai, UAE

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022

**Project**: TAMM, an eGovernance service platform for the Abu Dhabi Government. Tasked with developing the user journey of Abu Dhabi Digital Authority (ADDA).

- Completely WFH Squad collaboration using Slack, Workspace, management using JIRA, GitLab, documented on Confluence.
- Development primarily in ReactJS, NodeJS and ExpressJS, utilizing Redux and Camunda, including API development and payment gateway integration.
- Engineered along with 4 other developers in a cross-functional team of 15, for the targeted journey.
- Integrated existing services to the newly developed unified platform thereby applying the latest UI trends, better UX, reducing the process steps & time required, clicks and redirections, inducing approximately a 50% increase in efficiency and exponential growth in the userbase.

## **Full Stack Developer**

Freelance Development - Dubai, UAE

Mar 2021 – Sep 2021

**Projects**: Gulf Motorcycles Repairs & Rentals, United Piping Solutions, United International Piping UK, International Oilfield Supplies Oman, MarketPlace UAE

- Designed and developed websites, PWA admin panels, ERP systems using MERN and JAMstack, cross-platform mobile apps using React Native, online and print advertising campaigns [social media posts, logos, flyers, packaging, signboards, promotions] including video editing.
- Worked closely with managers and stakeholders for planning, designing and development iterations to ensure perfect delivery of planned products.

# MERRILL KOSHY THOMAS

+971-56-347-5735 / merrillkoshy@gmail.com / LinkedIn: in/merrill-koshy-thomas / Dubai, UAE

• Digitized 2 startups and a scaleup in a period of 6 months, singlehandedly delivering complete software and advertising solutions.

### **Full Stack Developer**

Sana'a Kayum - Dubai, UAE

Jul 2019 – Mar 2021

- Responsible for digitizing the entire experience of Sana'a Kayum eCommerce website and in-house web (NextJS | ExpressJS) & mobile apps (React Native), databases (MongoDB, Firebase) and CI/CD (GitHub | Vercel).
- Close collaboration with stakeholders on every phase, studied market patterns and the cross-functional team (fashion designers, tailors, sales and marketing) to provide efficient solutions in the iterative development approach.
- Led and collaborated with a team of 3 developers.
- Creating a substantial increase in brand visibility, the online presence created multiple avenues of sales like the introduction to the retail market and creating several lines of clothing, collectively increasing revenue by approximately 120.

#### Web and Software Developer

Dot10 Technical Services - Dubai, UAE

Nov 2017 – Jul 2019

Responsible for managing the digital department of the company. Heading the department,

- Retained the existing client base and scaled their products.
- Won 6 new projects while leading a cross-functional team.

As a Full Stack Developer:

- Designed and developed websites and mobile apps for 11 projects [including Mercedes-Benz] using ReactJS, WordPress and Kotlin.
- Integrated payment gateways, online booking and client-provided APIs thereby scaling existing services.
- Created and led online and print advertising campaigns [social media posts, logos, flyers, signboards, promotions] using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator, 3D modeling with SketchUp and video editing with Filmora.

#### **Programmer**

IPSR Solutions - Kerala, India

Feb 2017 - Sep 2017

**Project**: Site Health Checker

- Created an internal tool to inspect all the hosted sites of the company on their health checks with in-app reporting of
  site uptime and downtime, site traffic and hotspots thereby increasing service efficiency and reducing turnaround
  time.
- The project was built with Python using PyCharm and Tkinter, transitioning later to Kivy.
- Led by a Senior developer over a course of 8 months, inclusive of training.

#### **Software Engineer**

Soften technologies - Kerala, India

Jun 2016 – Jan 2017

**Project:** Travel with Glance

- Developed an Online Tourism Information System, which manages the user's trips, hotel stays and destinations with booking and time management.
- This included an Admin Module as well to onboard the user and facilitate the services provided.
- Built on C# and ASP.NET over a course of 8 months with 3 developers and a tech lead.

+971-56-347-5735 / merrillkoshy@gmail.com / LinkedIn: in/merrill-koshy-thomas / Dubai, UAE

## LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS & TOOLS

- ReactJS, React Native, NextJS, Razzle
- TypeScript, JavaScript, Jest, Enzyme
- Docker, GitHub, GitLab, Travis CI
- Storybook, JSDoc, Confluence
- JIRA, Workspace, Slack
- Microservices & RabbitMQ

- NodeJS, ExpressJS, NestJS, Camunda
- MongoDB, Contentful, Strapi, Firebase
- Netlify, Vercel, Heroku, Google App Engine
- GraphQL, Redux, JWT, Redis Caching
- Progressive Web Apps, NPM Packages
- Webpack, RollupJS

## ADDITIONAL ACQUIRED SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS
- Android Java, Kotlin
- Python, Django, Tkinter, Kivy, Flask
- Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch

- ASP.NET, C#, C++
- PHP, WordPress, JQuery
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- Blender, SketchUp, Filmora

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Engineering Mahatma Gandhi University

Jul 2015